# AYRON RIVERO

ayronribeiro.rr@gmail.com

Software Developer with over 5 years of experience, specializing in React, Angular, Wordpress and Strapi. Extensive experience in web development and API integration. Currently pursuing a postgraduate degree in Cybersecurity, incorporating cybersecurity best practices to enhance application security.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **POSTGRADUATE IN CYBERSECURITY**

Facuminas - Thesis approved with a score of 94 - 2023

# BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN SYSTEMS ANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT

Estácio de Sá, 2021

### **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, SASS, Strapi, React, Angular, Ionic, WordPress, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss, Figma, Git, RESTful API, GraphQL, SEO & Web Performance, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Supabase, AWS, Docker, Linux, CPanel, Protection against XSS, CSRF, SQL Injection, Agile Methodologies, Mobile-First Development & Responsive Design, Test Automation & Deployment.

# **COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

- English Robert Smyth Institute
- Angular Training Udemy
- Back-End Dev Immersion Alura
- Pentesting in Practice Desec Security
- UX Journey EBAC, 2024
- Ethical Hacking: Reconnaissance,
  Footprinting Pluralsight, 2024

# **LANGUAGES**

- English Advanced (C1)
- Portuguese: Native

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **WEEZAP**

Software Engineer | Founder & Owner - 2024 - Currently

Weezap is a platform for automating invoice reminders and payment requests via WhatsApp.

- Responsible for system architecture, including back-end, database, integrations, technology stack, and design.
- Used Next.js 14, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Shadon/UI, Prisma, PostgreSQL, and WebSockets for real-time features.
- Implemented authentication with NextAuth.js and JWT, ensuring security with route protection middleware.
- Integrated with external APIs, including WhatsApp Business and payment gateways.
- Applied Clean Architecture, TDD, and documentation with Storybook.

# **VRAUU ENERGY DRINK BRASIL**

Full-stack Developer - 2023 - Currently

- Developed and maintained the company's e-commerce and other websites, focusing on performance and user experience, using WordPress, WooCommerce, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, integrating the Bling API for inventory management and invoice generation.
- Managed Linux servers, hosting, domain, CPanel, backups, migrations, ensuring stability and security.
- Conducted usability, performance, and security testing, adhering to industry and implemented security best practices to protect against vulnerabilities such as XSS, CSRF, and SQL Injection.

#### **SOMOS.US**

Front-end Developer - 2021 - 2022

- Developed and customized over 30 WordPress websites, including core customizations, Elementor PRO, WPML, SEO tools integration, Google Analytics, and Facebook Pixel.
- Created a full-stack automated application using Strapi as CMS and API, built with Angular, Ionic, TypeScript, HTML, and SASS.
- Managed websites on WP Engine.
- Developed an internal automation tool that enabled the team to create landing pages independently using a custom CMS, removing the need for developer assistance.